Guide to the Victor Lloyd Butterfield Papers, 1910 - 1975
Victor Lloyd Butterfield Papers 1910 - 1975
- Butterfield Papers1910-1975
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "G" (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "H" (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "I" (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "J" (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "K" (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "L" (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "M" (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "N" (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "O" (Box 83, Folder 15)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "P" & "Q" (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "R" (Box 83, Folder 17)
  - Transcript of E. Lansing Conference (Box 83, Folder 18)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "S" (Box 83, Folder 19)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "T" (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "U" & "V" (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "W" & "X" (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Misc. Correspondence "Y" & "Z" (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Aid to Specific Scholars or Programs (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, American Council on Education (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Nominees for Future Meetings (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Communications with Former Participants (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Executive Committee Meetings (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, to S.C.L.S. (Executive Committee) (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Future Plans for S.C.L.S. (Agenda for Action) (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Memoranda to Participants (Box 84, Folder 12)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Participants Mailing List (Box 84, Folder 13)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Foundation Approaches (Box 84, Folder 14)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, AAC Meetings I, II, III & Pentagonal (Box 84, Folder 15)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Purpose and Program of S.C.L.S. (Box 84, Folder 16)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Visiting Committees (Box 84, Folder 17)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Suggestions from Participants (Box 84, Folder 18)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Unsolicited Correspondence (Box 84, Folder 19)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Carnegie Foundation (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Danforth Foundation (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, [Aspen Institute] (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Ford Foundation (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, General Service Foundation (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Hazen Foundation (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, J. Irwin Miller Philanthropies (Cummins Eng.) (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Pentagonal (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Association of American Colleges, Washington Meeting (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Association of American Colleges - Pending (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Association of American Colleges, Organization and Procedure (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - Association of American Colleges, Proposal to Danforth (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Pentagonal Meeting - Summary (Box 85, Folder 14)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Persons Recommended to Participate (Box 85, Folder 15)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Related Programs Materials - Comm. Undergraduate Teaching (Box 85, Folder 16)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Materials - Background (Box 85, Folder 17)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, September Meeting - Refusals (Box 85, Folder 18)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Participants to Date (Box 85, Folder 19)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, September Conference Correspondence (Box 85, Folder 20)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Correspondence (Box 85, Folder 21)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Statements, Purpose/Org. (Box 85, Folder 22)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Agenda for Regional Meeting (Box 85, Folder 23)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Programs Started by Participants (Box 85, Folder 24)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Projects and Funds (Box 85, Folder 25)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Finances (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Washington (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Aspen (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Aspen (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Barnard (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Barnard (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Notre Dame (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting Reports (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Report to Rockefeller Foundation (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - Association of American Colleges' Special Committee on Liberal Studies, Regional Meeting, Notre Dame, Indiana (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Post '67 Wesleyan (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - Wesleyan Department Budgets (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - President Search -- Wesleyan (Box 86, Folder 13)
  - AAC Special Committee on Liberal Studies (Box 86, Folder 14)
  - Town Meeting of the Air (Box 86, Folder 15)
  - Jacob, Changing Values in College, report for the Hazen Foundation (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Wesleyan By-law Revision (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Revision of By-Laws on Faculty Organization (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Personnel (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Itinerary (a typical year) (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Financial Aid Report (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Recruitment Personnel (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Staff Meetings (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Working Paper on Revision of the By-Laws of the Academic Council [Academic Council Revisions] (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous on By-Laws and Principles & Guidelines for Long-Range Planning and Development (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Educational Policy Committee, Agenda Items for 1966-67 (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, particularly re VLB illness in 1975 (Box 88, Folder 1-2)
  - Personal Items -- in cluding correspondence re American Education Press, etc. (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Personal odds & ends including football misc. and American Academy of Arts & Sciences Records (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Self-criticism -- Appreciations & Depreciations misc. correspondence & etc. praising or denigrating Wesleyan (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Wesleyan Interns -- Ford Foundation Grant correspondence from 1954-59 re teaching interns (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Letters of Recommendation (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - [Blane Mercer recommendations for Public Affairs Program leader] (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Organization Study (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Cornell and Deerfield -- misc. correspondence (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Long-Range Goals -- misc. reports & Correspondence on Educational Planning (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Wesleyan -- the New University 1961 a report, plus others on planning & Development (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - Faculty and Staff (Box 88, Folder 13)
    lists including addresses, leave schedules, tenure, retirement
  - Report of the Vice President and Treasurer year ended June 30, 1966 [confidential] (Box 88, Folder 14)
  - Association for Higher Education, correspondence (Box 88, Folder 15)
  - Humanities (articles on) (Box 88, Folder 16)
  - Goals for Wesleyan (Box 88, Folder 17)
    Misc. notes & correspondence
  - College Plan - Revised (Box 88, Folder 18)
    Report of Educational Policy Committee 1958. Correspondence 1973 (2)
  - Center for Advanced Studies (Box 88, Folder 19)
  - Advanced Learning (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Faculty Staffing Committee (Box 89, Folder 2)
    Includes President's Annual Report, notes on educational planning
  - Amherst Visiting Committee Report on Coeducation (Box 89, Folder 3)
    See Comments on Coeducation at Wesleyan
  - Michael Rapuano (Box 89, Folder 4)
    Correspondence, architectural consultant
  - Long Range Planning (Box 89, Folder 5)
    Working papers
  - College Plans (Box 89, Folder 6)
    Faculty memos, articles
  - Faculty Recruitment & Retention (Box 89, Folder 7)
    Correspondence, resume and reports re faculty recruitment
  - Wesleyan Current (Box 89, Folder 8)
    Misc.: Campbell's appointment as president, confidential reports on COL and ASS applicants, aptitude tests
  - Public Affairs, Urban Programs and University Outreach (Box 89, Folder 9)
    Various reports
  - Teacher Training & Local Schools (Box 89, Folder 10)
    Reports
  - Technology (Box 89, Folder 11)
    Herbert Blau
  - University Governance (Box 89, Folder 12)
    Proposed election procedure for advisory committee
  - Women's Undergraduate Education (Box 89, Folder 13)
    Report & memos
  - The Library (Box 89, Folder 14)
    SEPP report, W Parker's response
  - LR Planning (Box 89, Folder 15)
    Various working papers, Etherington Committee report, Educational Planning Committee
  - The Performing Arts (Box 89, Folder 16)
    Blau report to SEPP
  - Physical Education (Box 89, Folder 17)
    Reports from Kirkpatrick, McGill, Cochrane
  - Language Instruction (Box 89, Folder 18)
    Comments from Blau, etc.
  - Inter-Institutional Co-operation (Box 89, Folder 19)
    5 page report, no name
  - The College Plan (Box 89, Folder 20)
    Report from Ed. Policy Comm. 1958, 1 letter 1973, notes
  - Freshman year and General Curriculum (Box 89, Folder 21)
    1 page handwritten notes
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 89, Folder 22)
    Articles, notes
  - VLB schoolboy letters (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Letters written home from college (Cornell) (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Westfield Property (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Mostly letters of appreciation -- for dinners, misc. (Box 90, Folder 4-5)
  - Beta Theta Pi and early letters (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - VLB early talks and writings (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Letters of appreciation mostly one turn -down re Hobart Presidency (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - VLB's views on war, on universal military training (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Mostly letters of appreciation -- Harvard honorary degree, etc. (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Personal letters to VLB (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - VLB's views on fraternities, Important (Box 91, Folder 2)
    "A College President Looks at Fraternities" article by V.L.B. in Phi Mu Delta Triangle
  - VLB appointment to Wesleyan (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Mostly letters of appreciation (Box 91, Folder 4)
    Includes thank-you from Eleanor Wilson McAdoo, May Day incident
  - Family letters (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Football at Cornell - VLB and letters from his father (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Football, Important (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Letters of appreciation and inauguration clippings (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - VLB writings (Box 91, Folder 9)
    Doggerel, essays on liberal education, etc.
  - VLB membership in the Century Association (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Letters of appreciation -- Commencement (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - Misc. articles (Box 91, Folder 12)
    Report to Cornell on completing term as alumni trustee
  - Graduate study at Harvard -- VLB's PhD. (Box 91, Folder 13)
  - Butterfield, V.L. - Important Folder (Box 91, Folder 14)
    Miscellaneous statistics on class rankings; article by acting president; comments on Policy Committee report, 1940; draft letter to alumni re admissions; article on athletics; report on Middlesex School scholarships, 1935; correspondence with Pres. McConaughy re appointment
  - VLB policies (Box 91, Folder 15)
  - VLB inauguration notes (Box 91, Folder 16)
  - Guests at the inauguration of Victor Lloyd Butterfield (Box 92, Folder 1)
    Formerly catalogued separately for Wesleyan
  - Personal (Box 92, Folder 2)
    Includes exchange with Henry Wriston and Ernest Hocking
  - Letters on VLB's election to acting presidency (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Letters on VLB's election to presidency (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - VLB personal and important (Box 92, Folder 5)
    Includes material on 1948-49 controversy over tenure of junior faculty; offers of other presidencies; "Red Dean" controversy; 1941 problem of accepting Dennison Award
  - VLB and University of California at Santa Cruz (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Observations on Problems and Methods of the Small Liberal College, report to the Carnegie Corporation (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Personal miscellaneous (Box 93, Folder 2)
    Includes article in Deerfield Alumni Journal, Wisconsin Alumnus, correspondence with Chatham College, certificate from New England Board of Higher Education, article in Harvard Vlumni Bulletin
  - Commencement (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - VLB on TV program (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Howard Butterfield (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Personal matters, Includes honorary degree from Harvard, Westfield land negotiations (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Letters of appreciation (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Inauguration of VLB as President (Box 93, Folder 8)
    Bound volume
  - Retirement letters (Box 93, Folder 9)
    Clippings, photographs
  - Retirement letters (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous personal (Box 94, Folder 2-5)
  - Century Club -- personal (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences -- personal (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Auerbach, Beatrice -- personal (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Butterfield, V.L. (Box 94, Folder 9)
    Personal letters to his brother and others
  - Postretirement plans (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Personal matters (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Butterfield, V.L. (Box 95, Folder 3)
    Personal
  - Commencement (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Former trustees (Box 95, Folder 5)
    Allen, John C.; Baldwin, Horace S.; Blakey, William; Bonnet, Philip D.; Brengle, George S.; Buckingham, Harold; Budd, Edward; Davis, Donald; Davison, A.; Goode, M.; Gibbons, Willis; McClelland, Clarence P.
  - Trustees (Box 95, Folder 6)
    Kinsman, J. Warren; Newhall, Parker; Phillips, Harry; Houpert, Henri; Mooney, Wendell; Patricelli, Leonard; Peck, James K.; Petigrue, Winfred K.; Pullman, John; Russell, Charles A.; Ryder, Frank; Sutherland, A.E.; Upham, Francis B.; Vanderbilt, A.T.; White, Horace G.; White, William C.; Wing, Dudley
  - Burdick, C.D. (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Harriman, Henry I. (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Ingraham, Henry A. (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Johnston, Albert W. (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Newton, Clarence (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Edited draft manuscript, "Plan for Graduate Apprenticeship in Religious Studies, leading to Ph.D. degree" (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Wesleyan University Ten-Year Projections, 1966-67 - 1975-76 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Appointment calendars (Box 96, Folder 6-8)
  - Appointment calendars (Box 97, Folder 1-5)
  - Fellows, Center for Advanced Studies, M-W (Box 97, Folder 6)
    Meyer, L.B.; Petersen, Aage; Polanyi, Michael; Quine, W.V.; Rado, Tibor; Read, Herbert; Reiman, Donald; Schorske, Carl; Simmons, Ernest; Snoe, Charles P.; Snow, Lady Pamela J.; Stafford, Jean; Syme, R.; Streeten, Paul; Waddinton, C.H.; Whyte, L.; Wilson, Edmund
  - Faculty and staff recruitment book (Box 98, Folder 1)
    Small, 3-ring notebook
  - Foreign scholars (Box 98, Folder 2)
    1 leather notebook
  - Alumni talk (Box 98, Folder 3)
    9, 4x6 cards
  - Annual Report (Box 98, Folder 4)
    1 volume
  - Report of the Education Policy Committee to the Faculty of Wesleyan University (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Dance Magazine article on Wesleyan University Press (Box 98, Folder 6)
    1 issue
  - Alumni Views of Wesleyan University (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Riverdalian (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Long-range planning and educational considerations / Wesleyan (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Liberal Education journal (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Toward a Better Ministry, The Report of the Hazen Consultation on The Negro in the Christian Ministry (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Value Convictions and Higher Education (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Harvard Educational Review (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Religious Perspectives of College Teacching (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - "Being and Doing," reprint from University of Chicago Law Review (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - President's Ten-year Review & Annual Report 1971, The Rockefeller Foundation (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Agenda for the Colleges and Universities (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - ACLS Newsletter (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - The Graduage School Today and Tomorrow (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - "Students and Academic Freedom" (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - A Center Occasional Paper (Box 99, Folder 13)
    " So Reason Can Rule"; "Students and Society"
  - Vocational Analysis of Male College Graduates in Liberal Arts (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - The Creative Person (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Expenditure Summaries and Correspondence (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - A (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Adm. Organization chart (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Advanced learning (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Advanced learning - post doctorals (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Airlines (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Airport in Middletown (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - American education publications, inc. (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - Annuities (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - Alumni advisory board (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Alumni association and council (Box 100, Folder 13)
  - Alumni complaints (Box 100, Folder 14)
  - Alumni fund (WAF) (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Alumni secretary (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Alumni summer institute (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Archivist (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Associations (Box 101, Folder 5-9)
  - AAC special committee on liberal learning (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - Advisory committee of AAC (Box 102, Folder 1-2)
  - Athletic policy (Box 102, Folder 3-5)
  - B (Box 102, Folder 6)
    Correspondence
  - Birthday letters (Box 102, Folder 7)
    Outgoing, from VLB
  - Building committee re: sports building (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Bldgs & grounds, supt. (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Bldgs & grounds (Box 103, Folder 1-4)
  - Bursary program (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Business affairs budget
  - Business affairs faculty and staff tuition (Box 104)
  - Business affairs loans
  - Business affairs tuition
  - Business affairs treasurer
  - Business affairs vouchers
    Multiple tabs within file
  - C (Box 105)
  - Calendar
  - Centers for advanced study - various
  - Director of center - Paul Horgan
  - Center for advanced study - Tyler
  - Colleges
  - Colleges A-Z Co-ed for women (Box 106)
  - Colleges combined plans
  - College church
  - College plan college of letters
  - College plan evaluation of college plan
  - College plan general correspondence
  - College plan philosophy of college plan
  - College plan social studies
  - College plan quantitative studies
  - Commencement general
  - Commencement honorary degrees
  - Community college
  - Community service
  - Community improvement
  - Companion program
  - Computer lab
  - Communism
  - Counselling service
  - Commissioner of higher education - CT
  - Conn. Council on higher education
  - CT higher education facilities finance agency
  - CT legislation
  - CT, state of
  - Convocation
  - Creative Arts Center (Box 108)
  - D
  - Davison art collection
  - Dean of the college
  - Dean of the sciences
  - Discrimination
  - Drew, Charles, Mrs.
  - E
  - Endowment, possible donors
  - Etherington, Edwin D.
  - F (Box 109)
  - Faculty academic council
  - Faculty academic freedom
  - Faculty admission committee
  - Faculty advisory committee
  - Faculty campus art committee
  - Faculty committees
  - Faculty committee on faculty
  - Faculty department memos
  - Faculty educational policy committee
  - Faculty endowed professorships
  - Faculty committee on graduate instruction
  - Faculty meeting
  - Faculty salary policy
  - Faculty staff
  - Faculty fellowships and grants
  - Faculty fringe benefits
  - Faculty housing
  - Faculty junior faculty
  - Faculty leaves & sabbaticals
  - Faculty salaries
  - Fallout shelters
  - Foundations general correspondence
  - Surdna (Box 110)
  - Fraternities def. rushing
  - Fraternities discrimination
  - Fraternities general corresp.
  - Fraternity improvement
  - Fraternity Alpha Delta Phi
  - Fraternity Beta Theta Pi
  - Fraternity Chi Psi
  - Fraternity Commons Club
  - Fraternity Delta Kappa Epsilon (Box 111)
  - Fraternity Delta Sigma
  - Fraternity Delta Tau
  - Fraternity Eclectic
  - Fraternity EQV
  - Fraternity Gamma Psi
  - Fraternity John Wesley Club
  - Fraternity Kappa Alpha
  - Fraternity Kappa Nu Kappa
  - Fraternity Psi Upsilon
  - Fund raisers
  - G
  - Government grants atomic energy
  - Government grants HR 6143
  - Grants industrial
  - Ethnomusicology
  - Graduate division M.A.T.
  - Summer school
  - Government, U.S. federal aid
  - Government, U.S. Dept. H.E.W.
  - Government, U.S. Selective Service (Box 112)
  - Government, U.S. National Defense Loan
  - Government, U.S. presidential committee
  - Government, U.S. Presidential Committee on Scientists
  - Government, U.S. Social Security
  - Grants students
  - H
  - Health department
  - Hill development corporation real estate
  - History of Wesleyan